<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Doc List</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Doc List</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Dadgum Box Scores | Chris Gallo © 2017-2019.</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Efficiency</title>
      <link>/efficiency/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/efficiency/intro/</guid>
      <description>A team&amp;rsquo;s success comes down to its efficiency.
When a team has the ball, how easily does it score points?
When a team&amp;rsquo;s opponent has the ball, how easily does their opponent score points?
Efficiency answers both these questions.
In this section, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the different types of efficiency and how it&amp;rsquo;s measured.
 Possessions Offensive &amp;amp; Defensive Efficiency Combined Efficiency Tempo &amp;amp; Pace Adjusted Efficiency Average Possession Length  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Player Stats</title>
      <link>/player-stats/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/player-stats/intro/</guid>
      <description>The same way KenPom rates teams, players can also be evaluated.
In this section, you&amp;rsquo;ll find the different stats that go into assessing an individual player.
 Minutes played and possessions used Offensive rating (ORtg) Shooting (%Shots, eFG%, &amp;amp; TS%) Rebounding percentages (OR% &amp;amp; DR%) Assists and Turnovers Blocks &amp;amp; Steals Fouls  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Ratings</title>
      <link>/ratings/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ratings/intro/</guid>
      <description>This section covers KenPom ratings.
A team is rated based on its skill and opportunities. Or to put it more simply, a team is rated on its efficiency.
The ratings system is built on points scored or points allowed per possession.
KenPom&amp;rsquo;s system is predictive. It&amp;rsquo;s not meant to measure how good a team&amp;rsquo;s season is going. There are several polls all which have a mixed definition of what good means.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Resources</title>
      <link>/resources/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/intro/</guid>
      <description>First, the ultimate resource here is KenPom.com. A 12-month subscription is $19.95. It&amp;rsquo;s 100% worth it.
In the rest of this section, you&amp;rsquo;ll find the different resources that can help you learn more about college basketball advanced stats.
If you have a good resource that is not on this list, please send it to me.
 People to follow/know Books &amp;amp; Blogs Podcast Interviews  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Team Stats</title>
      <link>/team-stats/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team-stats/intro/</guid>
      <description>This section covers the how and the why behind a team&amp;rsquo;s performance.
Does a team have a ton of experience or height?
Does it shoot well from the 3 point-line or have an overwhelming presence in the paint?
And what match-up is worth watching or tuning in to?
In this section, we&amp;rsquo;ll answer each one of these questions.
 Team Offense Team Defense Points Distribution Personnel Stats  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to the Four Factors</title>
      <link>/four-factors/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/four-factors/intro/</guid>
      <description>The four factor concept comes from the mind of Dean Oliver.
Oliver believes four factors determine why a team wins or loses. The four factors are:
 Shooting Avoiding turnovers Offensive rebounding Getting to the foul line  A team is measured both offensively and defensively on these four factors.
Shooting The objective of the game is to score more points than the other team. And points come from made shots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purpose</title>
      <link>/about/purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/purpose/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this site to help people learn more about advanced analytics for college basketball.
None of the information on this site is new. You can find it all on Kenpom.com and other places on the web. This information is remixed and reshuffled to make it easier for you to digest.
The concepts listed on this site aren&amp;rsquo;t right. They aren&amp;rsquo;t wrong either. They&amp;rsquo;re just there for you to draw your own conclusions or maybe consider a new perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adjusted Efficiency Margin</title>
      <link>/ratings/adjusted-efficiency-margin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ratings/adjusted-efficiency-margin/</guid>
      <description>Adjusted Efficiency Margin, or AdjEM, is the difference between a team’s offensive and defensive efficiency.
AdjEM = AdjOE - AdjDE
AdjEM is used to rate teams. It was introduced by KenPom prior to the 2016-2017 season, and it&amp;rsquo;s detailed in this blog post. Prior to this metric, ratings were built on log5 and the Pythagorean expectation.
What does this mean? The adjusted efficiency margin shows the number of points a team would be expected to outscore the average Division-I team over 100 possessions without adjusting for location of the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective field goal percentage</title>
      <link>/four-factors/efg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/four-factors/efg/</guid>
      <description>This stat measures a team&amp;rsquo;s ability to shoot 2-point and 3-point shots.
A team&amp;rsquo;s field goal percentage is calculated by the number of shots attempted divided by the number of shots made. This includes both 2-point and 3-point shots.
FG% = FGM/FGA * 100
For example, in the 2018 NCAA Tournament Semifinal game between Villanova and Kansas, Villanova made 36 of its 65 shot attempts en route to scoring 95 points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minutes Played</title>
      <link>/player-stats/minutes-played/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/player-stats/minutes-played/</guid>
      <description>Minutes played measures how often a player is on the floor per game. This stat doesn&amp;rsquo;t factor in overtime games, so it can be a bit misleading.
KenPom uses a percentage of possible minutes played to account for overtime periods.
(%Min) = Minutes played / Possible Amount of Minutes
In the 2017-2018 season, Tyus Battle of Syracuse played in 96.2% of all minutes. This was good for 1st in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>/resources/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/people/</guid>
      <description>Below are a few well-respected people who write about college basketball analytics.
This list isn&amp;rsquo;t exhaustive. If you have someone worth following with interesting insights about advanced stats, please send me a suggestion and I&amp;rsquo;ll add it to this list.
Ken Pomeroy The inspiration for this site. Read and subscribe to KenPom.com. Follow @kenpomeroy too.
Dean Oliver Dean Oliver wrote Basketball on Paper, founded several advanced statistics, and has worked in the front office for multiple NBA teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Possessions</title>
      <link>/efficiency/possessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/efficiency/possessions/</guid>
      <description>Possessions are the foundation of a team&amp;rsquo;s offensive and defensive efficiency.
A team can&amp;rsquo;t score if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the ball.
Basketball has evolved over time all because of possessions.
Dean Smith ran the 4 Corner Offense to stall the game. In the 1982 ACC Championship game, North Carolina held the ball for almost 7 minutes in the second half and beat Virginia 47-45.
By 1985, the NCAA adopted a shot clock to end this strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Offense</title>
      <link>/team-stats/team-offense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team-stats/team-offense/</guid>
      <description>A team&amp;rsquo;s offense can be checked across 7 different stats:
 3P%: a team&amp;rsquo;s 3-point field goal percentage 2P%: a team&amp;rsquo;s 2-point field goal percentage FT%: a team&amp;rsquo;s free throw percentage Blk%: a team&amp;rsquo;s block percentage St%: a team&amp;rsquo;s steal percentage A%: a team&amp;rsquo;s assist percentage 3PA%: a team&amp;rsquo;s 3-point attempt percentage  3P% A team&amp;rsquo;s offensive 3-point field goal percentage is its made 3-point shots divided by its attempted 3-point shots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms</title>
      <link>/about/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/terms/</guid>
      <description>Copyright and Trademarks This site, cbbstatshelp.com, and all of its contents are owned by Chris Gallo. All rights reserved.
How can I use this information? Please don&amp;rsquo;t copy, distribute, or redistribute any information on this site. Yes, &amp;ldquo;fair use&amp;rdquo; is allowed. If you do use something or share, please cite help.dadgumboxscores.com as the source. Don&amp;rsquo;t be a jerk.
There are no guarantees when you use this site. Mistakes happen. If there is an error, something isn&amp;rsquo;t accurate, or if you want to use specific information, please send me an email and let me know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Turnovers</title>
      <link>/four-factors/turnovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/four-factors/turnovers/</guid>
      <description>When a team loses possession of the ball prior to shooting or scoring, it&amp;rsquo;s a turnover.
A team that rarely turns over the ball has more possessions and chances to score. The more chances you have to score, the better opportunity you have to win.
What percent of a team&amp;rsquo;s possessions result in a turnover?
The answer is a team&amp;rsquo;s turnover percentage.
TO% = TO / Possessions
For example, in the first regular season game between North Carolina and Duke, North Carolina turned the ball over 2 times over 65 possessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books and Blogs</title>
      <link>/resources/books-and-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/books-and-blogs/</guid>
      <description>Checkout a series of written resources on basketball analytics. And if you have a good resource not listed below, please send it my way.
Basketball on Paper This book is viewed as the Moneyball for Basketball. Written by Dean Oliver, Basketball on Paper, shares insights that help you think about basketball differently.
It presents information and lets you draw your own conclusions about how individual players and teams perform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luck</title>
      <link>/ratings/luck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ratings/luck/</guid>
      <description>Luck doesn&amp;rsquo;t factor into a team&amp;rsquo;s rating. It&amp;rsquo;s a metric that compares a team&amp;rsquo;s record to what they deserved based on their game-by-game efficiency.
If a team is involved in a lot of close games, it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t win or lose all of them. If a team wins all of the close games, they&amp;rsquo;re viewed as a lucky. An unlucky team would lose all of their close games.
Luck is measured using Dean Oliver&amp;rsquo;s correlated Gaussian method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Offensive Ratings</title>
      <link>/player-stats/offensive-ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/player-stats/offensive-ratings/</guid>
      <description>Remember a team&amp;rsquo;s offensive efficiency?
An individual player can be assessed using a similar measurement. This is a player&amp;rsquo;s Offensive Rating (ORtg).
This stat comes from the mind of Dean Oliver. Oliver defines the offensive rating:
Individual offensive rating is the number of points produced by a player per hundred total individual possessions.
This number tells you how many points a player is likely to score when given an opportunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Offensive and Defensive Efficiency</title>
      <link>/efficiency/offense-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/efficiency/offense-defense/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with Offensive Efficiency.
A team&amp;rsquo;s offensive efficiency is the amount of points it scores per 100 offensive possessions.
OE = (Points scored * 100) / Possessions
An Example
Let&amp;rsquo;s stick with the 2018 NCAA Tournament First Round game between Marshall and Wichita State.
Marshall had 72.45 possessions and scored 81 points. Its offensive efficiency was 112.
OE = (81 * 100) / 72.45 = 111.80
Wichita State scored 75 points over 72.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Defense</title>
      <link>/team-stats/team-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team-stats/team-defense/</guid>
      <description>A team&amp;rsquo;s defense can be evaluated using the same 7 stats:
 3P%: opponent&amp;rsquo;s 3-point field goal percentage 2P%: opponent&amp;rsquo;s 2-point field goal percentage FT%: opponent&amp;rsquo;s free throw percentage Blk%: opponent&amp;rsquo;s block percentage St%: opponent&amp;rsquo;s steal percentage A%: opponent&amp;rsquo;s assist percentage 3PA%: opponent&amp;rsquo;s 3-point attempt percentage  3P% A team&amp;rsquo;s defensive 3-point field goal percentage is its opponents&amp;rsquo; made 3-point shots divided by its opponents&amp;rsquo; attempted 3-point shots.
3P% = Opp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combined Efficiency</title>
      <link>/efficiency/combined-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/efficiency/combined-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>Combined efficiency is the number of points a team would gain or lose in 100 possessions. Take a team&amp;rsquo;s offensive efficiency and subtract the defensive efficiency.
Combined Efficiency = OE - DE
An Example
Using the same example of the 2018 NCAA Tournament First Round game between Marshall and Wichita State, Marshall&amp;rsquo;s offensive efficiency was 112 and its defensive efficiency was 104.
Marshall&amp;rsquo;s combined efficiency is 8.
Combined Efficiency = 112 - 104 = 8</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Offensive Rebounding</title>
      <link>/four-factors/offensive-rebounding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/four-factors/offensive-rebounding/</guid>
      <description>A team&amp;rsquo;s ability to increase its number of possessions, gives it a greater chance to score points and win games. Offensive rebounding is the main factor for a team to gain possessions.
This is measured by offensive rebounding percentage or the percentage of offensive rebounds a team grabs over the course of a game or season.
OR% = Offensive Rebounds / (Offensive Rebounds + Opponent&#39;s Defensive Rebounds)
For example, over the entire 2017-2018 season Duke&amp;rsquo;s Offensive Rebounding Percentage was 38.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overall Strength of Schedule</title>
      <link>/ratings/overall-sos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ratings/overall-sos/</guid>
      <description>A team&amp;rsquo;s strength of schedule is made up of 3 components.
The 3 components:
 AdjEM is the overall strength of schedule of a team AdjO - Opponent&amp;rsquo;s average adjusted offensive efficiency AdjD - Opponent&amp;rsquo;s average adjusted defensive efficiency  AdjEM for strength of schedule is calculated:
AdjEM of SOS = AdjO - AdjD
A team&amp;rsquo;s AdjEM for SOS is difference between the average of its opponents&amp;rsquo; offensive and defensive efficiencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Interviews</title>
      <link>/resources/podcast-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/podcast-interviews/</guid>
      <description>If you like consuming information about basketball analytics in a different way, you might find these recent interviews interesting.
If there is a video or podcast or interview not on this list and you think it would be helpful, please let me know.
Solving Basketball Podcast Jordan Sperber chats with Ken Pomeroy on the first episode of his podcast. Jordan has a unique perspective working with coaches and teams closely over the last few years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Points Distribution</title>
      <link>/team-stats/points-distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team-stats/points-distribution/</guid>
      <description>How a team gets its points can be broken down into 3 areas:
 Free throws: total points on made free throws 2-Point shots: total points on made 2-point shots 3-Point shots: total points on made 3-point shots  This breakdown describes the style of a team and its strengths. Each category can be used to assess a team&amp;rsquo;s offensive and defensive point distribution.
Offensive Point Distribution This section shares examples of a team&amp;rsquo;s offensive distribution of points in these 3 categories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shooting</title>
      <link>/player-stats/shooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/player-stats/shooting/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ll look at 3 calculations here to measure a player&amp;rsquo;s ability to shoot:
 %Shots eFG% TS%  Percentage of shots taken When a player is on the court, how many shots does the player attempt compared the rest of the team?
A percentage of shots taken is measured by taking a players&amp;rsquo; field goal attempts divided by its percentage of minutes played multiplied by its team&amp;rsquo;s field goal attempts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting to the foul line</title>
      <link>/four-factors/free-throw-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/four-factors/free-throw-rate/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s called the charity stripe for a reason. A team that gets fouled in the act of shooting or over and over again in a game, gets to shoot free throws.
The more free throws a team attempts, the better opportunity it has to score and win games.
This is measured through a team&amp;rsquo;s free throw rate.
FTRate = FTA / FGA
The amount of free throw attempts divided by the amount of field goal attempts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personnel Stats</title>
      <link>/team-stats/personnel-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team-stats/personnel-stats/</guid>
      <description>A team&amp;rsquo;s personnel can be measured across 5 different categories:
 Height: total height of a team weighted by minutes played Bench Minutes: the number of minutes a team&amp;rsquo;s bench plays Continuity: minutes played season-to-season Experience: year in school weighted by minutes played Defensive Fingerprint: identifies the style of a team&amp;rsquo;s defense 2-Foul Participation: percentage of time a starter with 2 fouls plays in the first half  Assumptions are made for each of these components, and detailed explanations are below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rebounding</title>
      <link>/player-stats/rebounding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/player-stats/rebounding/</guid>
      <description>An individual player&amp;rsquo;s ability to rebound increases its team&amp;rsquo;s possessions. There are 2 percentages used to measure a player&amp;rsquo;s ability to grab rebounds.
 Offensive rebounding percentage (OR%) Defensive rebounding percentage (DR%)  Offensive Rebounding Percentage What is the percentage of offensive rebounds a player gets?
This is calculated by incorporating a player&amp;rsquo;s total offensive rebounds, percentage of minutes played, a team&amp;rsquo;s total offensive rebounds, and opponent&amp;rsquo;s defensive rebounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats Glossary</title>
      <link>/resources/stats-glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/stats-glossary/</guid>
      <description>Miscellaneous stats FG: Field goals
FGA: Field goal attempts (2 or 3-point shots)
FGM: Field goal makes (2 or 3-point made shots)
TO: Turnovers
FTA: Free throw attempts
FTM: Free throw makes
OR: Offensive rebound
DR: Defensive rebound
3PA: 3-point shot attempts
3PM: 3-point shot makes
2PA: 2-point shot attempts
2PM: 2-point shot makes
Team rebound: A rebound that doesn&amp;rsquo;t fall into the possession of an individual player.
Four Factors eFG%: effective field goal percentage</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tempo and Pace</title>
      <link>/efficiency/tempo-and-pace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/efficiency/tempo-and-pace/</guid>
      <description>Tempo or pace is the number of possessions a team uses in a game.
Remember the 4 Corner offense? Dean Smith preferred to play a slower tempo to limit their opponents&amp;rsquo; possessions.
Today, there is a shot clock, and the 4 Corner offense likely wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be as effective.
Why is tempo or pace important? Not all teams have the same preferences. Some teams like to play fast or up-tempo. Other teams want to slow the game down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tiers</title>
      <link>/ratings/tiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ratings/tiers/</guid>
      <description>While a team&amp;rsquo;s strength of schedule can give you an idea about how they stack up to competition, how do you know if a team has quality wins or losses?
Tiers can help answer this question.
KenPom defines 2 tiers:
 Tier A: a game against a top-50 opponent adjusted for location of the game Tier B: a game against a top-100 opponent adjusted for location of the game  Why make adjustments for location?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adjusted Efficiency</title>
      <link>/efficiency/adjusted-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/efficiency/adjusted-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>Offensive and defensive efficiency come directly from a box score. The four factors lead to the amount of points a team scores and how they choose to play contributes to the amount of possessions a team uses.
It&amp;rsquo;s raw information. The raw offensive efficiency and raw defensive efficiency don&amp;rsquo;t factor in competition.
Why is this important? Here are 2 additional examples of the importance of adjusted efficiencies using KenPom&amp;rsquo;s analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assists and Turnovers</title>
      <link>/player-stats/assists-and-turnovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/player-stats/assists-and-turnovers/</guid>
      <description>An individual player&amp;rsquo;s ability to distribute the ball and avoid turnovers is measured by 2 stats.
 Assist Rate Turnover Rate  Assist Rate A player&amp;rsquo;s assist rate is computed by taking a player&amp;rsquo;s total assists divided by the made field goals by the player&amp;rsquo;s teammates while the player is on the court.
Here is the calculation:
ARate = 100 * AST / (((MP / (Team&#39;s MP / 5)) * Team&#39;s FG) - FG)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Average Possession Length</title>
      <link>/efficiency/apl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/efficiency/apl/</guid>
      <description>Tempo or pace shows how a team prefers to play. A team&amp;rsquo;s style.
Do they play up-tempo? Do they like to slow it down? Do they play man-to-man defense? Or zone?
A lot of these questions can be answered calculating a team&amp;rsquo;s average possession length.
Average possession length is a closer look at a team&amp;rsquo;s pace. It&amp;rsquo;s a new metric, and KenPom introduces it in this article.
APL = a team&#39;s seconds on offense and defense</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blocks and Steals</title>
      <link>/player-stats/blocks-and-steals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/player-stats/blocks-and-steals/</guid>
      <description>A player&amp;rsquo;s defensive ability can be measured using blocks and steals.
 Block Percentage (%Blocks) Steal Percentage (%Stls)  Block Percentage Block percentage is the percentage of opponents&amp;rsquo; 2-point shots that are blocked by an individual player while he&amp;rsquo;s on the floor.
%Blocks = Total Player&#39;s Blocks / (%Min * Opponents&#39; 2-point attempts)
For example, Sagaba Konate of West Virginia posted a 15.64 block percentage in the 2017-2018 season. A block percentage of 15.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fouls</title>
      <link>/player-stats/fouls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/player-stats/fouls/</guid>
      <description>There are 3 metrics that indicate how fouls factor into an individual&amp;rsquo;s effectiveness:
 Free Throw Rate (FTRate) Fouls committed per 40 minutes played (FC/40) Fouls drawn per 40 minutes played (FD/40)  Free Throw Rate (FTRate) Free throw rate measures a player&amp;rsquo;s ability to get to the foul line relative to how often he attempts to score. It takes a players free throw attempts and divides those attempts by the player&amp;rsquo;s total field goal attempts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>