<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Efficiency on Doc List</title>
    <link>gethugothemes.com/efficiency/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Efficiency on Doc List</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Dadgum Box Scores | Chris Gallo © 2017-2019.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="gethugothemes.com/efficiency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Efficiency</title>
      <link>gethugothemes.com/efficiency/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>gethugothemes.com/efficiency/intro/</guid>
      <description>A team&amp;rsquo;s success comes down to its efficiency.
When a team has the ball, how easily does it score points?
When a team&amp;rsquo;s opponent has the ball, how easily does their opponent score points?
Efficiency answers both these questions.
In this section, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the different types of efficiency and how it&amp;rsquo;s measured.
 Possessions Offensive &amp;amp; Defensive Efficiency Combined Efficiency Tempo &amp;amp; Pace Adjusted Efficiency Average Possession Length  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Possessions</title>
      <link>gethugothemes.com/efficiency/possessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>gethugothemes.com/efficiency/possessions/</guid>
      <description>Possessions are the foundation of a team&amp;rsquo;s offensive and defensive efficiency.
A team can&amp;rsquo;t score if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the ball.
Basketball has evolved over time all because of possessions.
Dean Smith ran the 4 Corner Offense to stall the game. In the 1982 ACC Championship game, North Carolina held the ball for almost 7 minutes in the second half and beat Virginia 47-45.
By 1985, the NCAA adopted a shot clock to end this strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Offensive and Defensive Efficiency</title>
      <link>gethugothemes.com/efficiency/offense-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>gethugothemes.com/efficiency/offense-defense/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with Offensive Efficiency.
A team&amp;rsquo;s offensive efficiency is the amount of points it scores per 100 offensive possessions.
OE = (Points scored * 100) / Possessions
An Example
Let&amp;rsquo;s stick with the 2018 NCAA Tournament First Round game between Marshall and Wichita State.
Marshall had 72.45 possessions and scored 81 points. Its offensive efficiency was 112.
OE = (81 * 100) / 72.45 = 111.80
Wichita State scored 75 points over 72.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combined Efficiency</title>
      <link>gethugothemes.com/efficiency/combined-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>gethugothemes.com/efficiency/combined-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>Combined efficiency is the number of points a team would gain or lose in 100 possessions. Take a team&amp;rsquo;s offensive efficiency and subtract the defensive efficiency.
Combined Efficiency = OE - DE
An Example
Using the same example of the 2018 NCAA Tournament First Round game between Marshall and Wichita State, Marshall&amp;rsquo;s offensive efficiency was 112 and its defensive efficiency was 104.
Marshall&amp;rsquo;s combined efficiency is 8.
Combined Efficiency = 112 - 104 = 8</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tempo and Pace</title>
      <link>gethugothemes.com/efficiency/tempo-and-pace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>gethugothemes.com/efficiency/tempo-and-pace/</guid>
      <description>Tempo or pace is the number of possessions a team uses in a game.
Remember the 4 Corner offense? Dean Smith preferred to play a slower tempo to limit their opponents&amp;rsquo; possessions.
Today, there is a shot clock, and the 4 Corner offense likely wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be as effective.
Why is tempo or pace important? Not all teams have the same preferences. Some teams like to play fast or up-tempo. Other teams want to slow the game down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adjusted Efficiency</title>
      <link>gethugothemes.com/efficiency/adjusted-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>gethugothemes.com/efficiency/adjusted-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>Offensive and defensive efficiency come directly from a box score. The four factors lead to the amount of points a team scores and how they choose to play contributes to the amount of possessions a team uses.
It&amp;rsquo;s raw information. The raw offensive efficiency and raw defensive efficiency don&amp;rsquo;t factor in competition.
Why is this important? Here are 2 additional examples of the importance of adjusted efficiencies using KenPom&amp;rsquo;s analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Average Possession Length</title>
      <link>gethugothemes.com/efficiency/apl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>gethugothemes.com/efficiency/apl/</guid>
      <description>Tempo or pace shows how a team prefers to play. A team&amp;rsquo;s style.
Do they play up-tempo? Do they like to slow it down? Do they play man-to-man defense? Or zone?
A lot of these questions can be answered calculating a team&amp;rsquo;s average possession length.
Average possession length is a closer look at a team&amp;rsquo;s pace. It&amp;rsquo;s a new metric, and KenPom introduces it in this article.
APL = a team&#39;s seconds on offense and defense</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>