<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resources on Doc List</title>
    <link>/resources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resources on Doc List</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Dadgum Box Scores | Chris Gallo © 2017-2019.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Resources</title>
      <link>/resources/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/intro/</guid>
      <description>First, the ultimate resource here is KenPom.com. A 12-month subscription is $19.95. It&amp;rsquo;s 100% worth it.
In the rest of this section, you&amp;rsquo;ll find the different resources that can help you learn more about college basketball advanced stats.
If you have a good resource that is not on this list, please send it to me.
 People to follow/know Books &amp;amp; Blogs Podcast Interviews  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>/resources/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/people/</guid>
      <description>Below are a few well-respected people who write about college basketball analytics.
This list isn&amp;rsquo;t exhaustive. If you have someone worth following with interesting insights about advanced stats, please send me a suggestion and I&amp;rsquo;ll add it to this list.
Ken Pomeroy The inspiration for this site. Read and subscribe to KenPom.com. Follow @kenpomeroy too.
Dean Oliver Dean Oliver wrote Basketball on Paper, founded several advanced statistics, and has worked in the front office for multiple NBA teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books and Blogs</title>
      <link>/resources/books-and-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/books-and-blogs/</guid>
      <description>Checkout a series of written resources on basketball analytics. And if you have a good resource not listed below, please send it my way.
Basketball on Paper This book is viewed as the Moneyball for Basketball. Written by Dean Oliver, Basketball on Paper, shares insights that help you think about basketball differently.
It presents information and lets you draw your own conclusions about how individual players and teams perform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Interviews</title>
      <link>/resources/podcast-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/podcast-interviews/</guid>
      <description>If you like consuming information about basketball analytics in a different way, you might find these recent interviews interesting.
If there is a video or podcast or interview not on this list and you think it would be helpful, please let me know.
Solving Basketball Podcast Jordan Sperber chats with Ken Pomeroy on the first episode of his podcast. Jordan has a unique perspective working with coaches and teams closely over the last few years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats Glossary</title>
      <link>/resources/stats-glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/stats-glossary/</guid>
      <description>Miscellaneous stats FG: Field goals
FGA: Field goal attempts (2 or 3-point shots)
FGM: Field goal makes (2 or 3-point made shots)
TO: Turnovers
FTA: Free throw attempts
FTM: Free throw makes
OR: Offensive rebound
DR: Defensive rebound
3PA: 3-point shot attempts
3PM: 3-point shot makes
2PA: 2-point shot attempts
2PM: 2-point shot makes
Team rebound: A rebound that doesn&amp;rsquo;t fall into the possession of an individual player.
Four Factors eFG%: effective field goal percentage</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>