<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ratings on CBB Stats Help</title>
    <link>/ratings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ratings on CBB Stats Help</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Dadgum Box Scores | Chris Gallo © 2017-2019.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/ratings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Ratings</title>
      <link>/ratings/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ratings/intro/</guid>
      <description>This section covers KenPom ratings.
A team is rated based on its skill and opportunities. Or to put it more simply, a team is rated on its efficiency.
The ratings system is built on points scored or points allowed per possession.
KenPom&amp;rsquo;s system is predictive. It&amp;rsquo;s not meant to measure how good a team&amp;rsquo;s season is going. There are several polls all which have a mixed definition of what good means.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adjusted Efficiency Margin</title>
      <link>/ratings/adjusted-efficiency-margin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ratings/adjusted-efficiency-margin/</guid>
      <description>Adjusted Efficiency Margin, or AdjEM, is the difference between a team’s offensive and defensive efficiency.
AdjEM = AdjOE - AdjDE
AdjEM is used to rate teams. It was introduced by KenPom prior to the 2016-2017 season, and it&amp;rsquo;s detailed in this blog post. Prior to this metric, ratings were built on log5 and the Pythagorean expectation.
What does this mean? The adjusted efficiency margin shows the number of points a team would be expected to outscore the average Division-I team over 100 possessions without adjusting for location of the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luck</title>
      <link>/ratings/luck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ratings/luck/</guid>
      <description>Luck doesn&amp;rsquo;t factor into a team&amp;rsquo;s rating. It&amp;rsquo;s a metric that compares a team&amp;rsquo;s record to what they deserved based on their game-by-game efficiency.
If a team is involved in a lot of close games, it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t win or lose all of them. If a team wins all of the close games, they&amp;rsquo;re viewed as a lucky. An unlucky team would lose all of their close games.
Luck is measured using Dean Oliver&amp;rsquo;s correlated Gaussian method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overall Strength of Schedule</title>
      <link>/ratings/overall-sos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ratings/overall-sos/</guid>
      <description>A team&amp;rsquo;s strength of schedule is made up of 3 components.
The 3 components:
 AdjEM is the overall strength of schedule of a team AdjO - Opponent&amp;rsquo;s average adjusted offensive efficiency AdjD - Opponent&amp;rsquo;s average adjusted defensive efficiency  AdjEM for strength of schedule is calculated:
AdjEM of SOS = AdjO - AdjD
A team&amp;rsquo;s AdjEM for SOS is difference between the average of its opponents&amp;rsquo; offensive and defensive efficiencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tiers</title>
      <link>/ratings/tiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ratings/tiers/</guid>
      <description>While a team&amp;rsquo;s strength of schedule can give you an idea about how they stack up to competition, how do you know if a team has quality wins or losses?
Tiers can help answer this question.
KenPom defines 2 tiers:
 Tier A: a game against a top-50 opponent adjusted for location of the game Tier B: a game against a top-100 opponent adjusted for location of the game  Why make adjustments for location?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>