<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Four Factors on Doc List</title>
    <link>gethugothemes.com/four-factors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Four Factors on Doc List</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Dadgum Box Scores | Chris Gallo © 2017-2019.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="gethugothemes.com/four-factors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to the Four Factors</title>
      <link>gethugothemes.com/four-factors/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>gethugothemes.com/four-factors/intro/</guid>
      <description>The four factor concept comes from the mind of Dean Oliver.
Oliver believes four factors determine why a team wins or loses. The four factors are:
 Shooting Avoiding turnovers Offensive rebounding Getting to the foul line  A team is measured both offensively and defensively on these four factors.
Shooting The objective of the game is to score more points than the other team. And points come from made shots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective field goal percentage</title>
      <link>gethugothemes.com/four-factors/efg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>gethugothemes.com/four-factors/efg/</guid>
      <description>This stat measures a team&amp;rsquo;s ability to shoot 2-point and 3-point shots.
A team&amp;rsquo;s field goal percentage is calculated by the number of shots attempted divided by the number of shots made. This includes both 2-point and 3-point shots.
FG% = FGM/FGA * 100
For example, in the 2018 NCAA Tournament Semifinal game between Villanova and Kansas, Villanova made 36 of its 65 shot attempts en route to scoring 95 points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Turnovers</title>
      <link>gethugothemes.com/four-factors/turnovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>gethugothemes.com/four-factors/turnovers/</guid>
      <description>When a team loses possession of the ball prior to shooting or scoring, it&amp;rsquo;s a turnover.
A team that rarely turns over the ball has more possessions and chances to score. The more chances you have to score, the better opportunity you have to win.
What percent of a team&amp;rsquo;s possessions result in a turnover?
The answer is a team&amp;rsquo;s turnover percentage.
TO% = TO / Possessions
For example, in the first regular season game between North Carolina and Duke, North Carolina turned the ball over 2 times over 65 possessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Offensive Rebounding</title>
      <link>gethugothemes.com/four-factors/offensive-rebounding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>gethugothemes.com/four-factors/offensive-rebounding/</guid>
      <description>A team&amp;rsquo;s ability to increase its number of possessions, gives it a greater chance to score points and win games. Offensive rebounding is the main factor for a team to gain possessions.
This is measured by offensive rebounding percentage or the percentage of offensive rebounds a team grabs over the course of a game or season.
OR% = Offensive Rebounds / (Offensive Rebounds + Opponent&#39;s Defensive Rebounds)
For example, over the entire 2017-2018 season Duke&amp;rsquo;s Offensive Rebounding Percentage was 38.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting to the foul line</title>
      <link>gethugothemes.com/four-factors/free-throw-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>gethugothemes.com/four-factors/free-throw-rate/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s called the charity stripe for a reason. A team that gets fouled in the act of shooting or over and over again in a game, gets to shoot free throws.
The more free throws a team attempts, the better opportunity it has to score and win games.
This is measured through a team&amp;rsquo;s free throw rate.
FTRate = FTA / FGA
The amount of free throw attempts divided by the amount of field goal attempts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>